vivahabandhan.com 2010-04-20

# Vivabandhan privacy policies: Read and Register for Free to search your soulmate

Information the Website collects and How It's Used

Profiles 

www.vivahabandhan.com ("Website") is an online matrimonial service designed to provide an easy way for its members to meet each other on the Web. To accomplish this, the Website collects personal information which is used in order to find matches which offer the highest possible chance of successful marriages. Except as explicitly provided herein, none of the information collected by the Website as part of the questionnaire used by the matching engine or personality profile is made accessible to the public, other users of the Website or anyone not employed by the Website directly. This information is held strictly confidential and can be deleted at the user's request. Information collected through the profile may be shared with other users of the Website but will be displayed in a strictly anonymous manner with no personally identifying details, and will only be shown to potential match candidates. Visitors to the website may browse the site, search member profiles and view any articles or features the Website has to offer without entering any personal information. 

Information Supplied by You at Registration or Payment of Subscription Fees

To process subscriptions, the Website may require information - your name, billing address, phone number, email address and credit card information. You will receive one email notification that your payment has been received, and another email notification confirming the activation of the Premier Membership services (as defined in the Website's Terms and Conditions). You will be notified of subscription renewal transactions when they occur. Email contact information provided by you is used primarily to notify you of potential match candidates identified by the Website based on your matching criteria and profile. Once you commence the Website's registration process, the Website may occasionally send newsletters and email notifications of special events or product offerings at the Website. If you start, but do not complete, the registration process, the Website may also send email messages encouraging you to complete the process and become a subscriber and/or Premier Member. All of the email messages the Website sends you may contain a code that enables the Website's database to track your usage of the emails, including whether the email was opened and/or what links (if any) were clicked. If you choose not receive emails about new products, promotions or other noteworthy news, please see the section below labeled "Choice/Opt-out". 

Advertisements, promotions and offers from third-party advertisers may be provided to you while you visit the Website. Similarly when paying the Website subscription fees, advertisements, promotions and offers from third-party advertisers may be provided to you. If you choose to accept any such offers, the Website may provide your information, including billing information, to the advertiser. Your information will not be transferred until you actually accept the offer. You may opt-out of the offer at any time up until this point.  Please refer to the third-party advertisers own privacy policy (provided on the offer pages) if you have questions regarding how your information is used. Please be aware that these offers may be presented on pages framed by the Website. The Website does this to provide a seamless experience. Although these offer pages have the look and feel of Website, you will be submitting your information directly to the third-party advertiser.

From time-to-time the Website requests information from you via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. 

Credit card transactions are processed through industry standard secure socket layer encryption by a third party, which only uses your information for that purpose.

The Website will only share your information with third-parties in the ways defined in this privacy statement.

Information Supplied by Your Browser

Website also logs IP addresses for systems administration purposes. IP addresses are logged to track a user's session. The Website does not link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable. Therefore though the user's session will be tracked, but the user will remain anonymous. 

The Website uses cookies to keep track of some types of information while you are visiting or using the Website. Cookies are needed for the Website to operate properly. They facilitate your ongoing access to and use of the Website and allow a site to track usage behavior, they also help compile aggregate data for content improvements; and undertake targeted advertising. If your browser is set to reject all cookies, the Website will not function properly. 

Third-Party Advertising

The Website may use third-party advertising agencies to serve ads on behalf of the Website or third-party advertisers (e.g., retailers of goods or services). These companies may employ cookies and action tags (also known as single pixel gifs or web beacons) to measure advertising effectiveness. Any information that these third parties collect via cookies and action tags is completely anonymous. 

Legal Disclaimer

Though the Website makes every effort to preserve user privacy, the Website may disclose information you provide if required to do so by law, enforcement agency or court order or if the Website has a good faith belief that disclosure is necessary to (1) comply with the law or with legal process served on us; (2) protect and defend its rights or property; (3) act in an emergency to protect someone's safety or (4) as expressly provided herein. 

The Website also may disclose this information to its subsidiary and parent companies and businesses, and other affiliated legal entities and businesses with who the Website is under common corporate control. However, all of these parent, subsidiary and affiliated legal entities and businesses that receive your personal information from the Website will comply with the terms of this privacy policy with respect to their use and disclosure of such personal information.

Age Restrictions

The Website will not create matches for anyone not within the legally marriageable age. Any information received by the Website from a person the Website believes to be a minor will be purged from its database. 

Public Forums

The Website makes message boards available to its users and visitors. Information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information. 

Security

The Website has extensive security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information stored in its database. These measures include the use of Secure Server technology during credit card transactions and administrative access to site data, as well as other proprietary security measures which are applied to all repositories and transfers of user information. The Website shall exercise reasonable care in providing secure transmission of information between your computer and the Website's servers, the Website cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information transmitted to the Website over the Internet and the shall accept no liability for any unintentional disclosure. 

Pointers to protect your privacy [Optional Clause]

Please take the following steps to further protect your privacy:

  1. Always close your browser and log out from the Website once you have finished surfing the net to prevent other people gaining access to your information and correspondence. 
  2. The Website has no control over other websites that it may be link to, and the Website takes no responsibility for the conduct of these companies. Always read the Terms and Conditions when using other websites. 
  3. Keep your passwords and your member details secret. If unauthorized access of your account occurs please inform us immediately. Frequently change your password. 
  4. Posting of personal contact information is prohibited on the Website. The Website takes no responsibility for any personal contact information disclosed to other members in its network. Personal information includes information such as full names, telephone numbers and home addresses. Beware - if you voluntarily disclose personal information it may be collected and used by others. 

Policies and Remedies [Optional Clause] Links to Other Sites

The Website is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other websites that may be linked to the Website or of any third party advertisers. 

Choice/Opt-Out

You may send an email to support@vivahabandhan.com with the word "Remove" in the subject field if they do not wish to receive future communications from the Website.

You can also opt-out of receiving promotional emails and newsletters by clicking on the "Email Settings" link on your Account Settings page and un-checking the undesired promotions. 

Correct/Update

You shall have the following options for changing and modifying information previously submitted. 

  1. Users may change their credit card, password and other information by going to User Settings page and selecting "My Account" link in the top navigation area; 
  2. You can send email to admin@vivahabandhan.com.

Contacting the Website

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of the Website, you may send an email to admin@vivahabandhan.com.

ACCEPTANCE OF PRIVACY STATEMENT 

Your use of Website, including any dispute concerning privacy, is subject to this privacy statement and the Terms and Conditions of Service. 

BY USING THE WEBSITE, YOU ARE ACCEPTING THE PRACTICES SET OUT IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF SERVICE.

If the Website decides to change its privacy policy, the Website will post those changes to this privacy statement page and any other places it deems appropriate so that you are aware of what information the Website collects, how the Website uses it, and under what circumstances, if any, the Website discloses it. The Website reserves the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If the Website makes material changes to this policy, the Website will notify you here, or by other means, such as email, at its discretion.

Your continued use of any portion of the Website following posting of the updated privacy statement will constitute your acceptance of the changes.

Effective Date

This privacy policy comes into effect on the date of registration. [Note: Please insert a date here. Also as and when the policy is revised you may amend this statement to say; "This privacy policy was last revised on [ ___]"] [In the alternate you may delete this clause on "Effective Date"].
